Daniel Williams

Columbus, Ohio | 602-697-8360 | danielpaulwill@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack developer skilled in JavaScript, React, Ruby, and Rails with a passion for learning and optimizing systems and processes to help businesses improve quality and consistency. Past senior commercial photographer with experience in delivering results both individually and as a lead in a team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Engineering: Javascript (ES6), React, Node.js, Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, Git, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap **Design:** Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Wayfarer: Journey to Understanding - Github | Video Demo

An 8-bit multiple choice mystery RPG with some shocking twists and turns.

Technologies used: JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS

- Developed REST Rails API and utilized Rails to serve complex data to React front-end.
- Designed the frontend from the ground up to resemble a classic 8-Bit game.
- Programmed custom character creation that will influence game interactions and outcome using React Hooks.

Starbucks Confidential - Github | Live Demo

An informational app that brings you the unlisted caffeine content of popular bottled Starbucks drinks.

Technologies used: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap

- Designed custom API to deliver hard to find drink nutrition information to the React frontend.
- Created filterable results and a "favorites" feature so you can easily find your favorite drinks.
- Utilized CSS and React State to reveal and hide drink info to keep the visual design clean and organized.

CryptoFinder - Github | Live Demo

A cryptocurrency app that allows users to have the information they need to make informed investment decisions. *Technologies used: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap*

- Leveraged a live Cryptocurrency API to show current prices as well as show market change data.
- Implemented Bootstrap to ensure the app is mobile ready.
- Included countdown timer for data refresh to reassure users that data is current.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Timshel StudiosColumbus, OhioCo-Owner / Photographer2012 - Present

• Worked with creative agencies and direct clients across the U.S. and the U.K including Walmart, Victoria's Secret, The Home Depot, Newell Brands, Sharpie, and Graco.

DSW Designer Shoe Warehouse

Columbus, Ohio 01/2022 - Present

Senior Photographer

- Lead photography team and digital marketing photo shoots for high priority projects.
- Developed and implemented weekly audits to ensure regular QA website checks.

Sarnova Columbus, Ohio Lead Photographer 10/2019 - 01/2022

- Revamped the studio which resulted in a 400% increase in output and a 43% reduction in customer complaints.
- Managed studio and implemented multifaceted reporting to track output which led to significant resource reallocation.
- Lead asset migration project from old website to new platform ahead of schedule and totalled over 9,800 images.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Columbus, Ohio

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

John Brown University

Siloam Springs, Arkansas

2022